Lucas Richards | Full Stack Software Engineer

Irvine, CA 92604 | 949-241-5305 | lucasandrewrichards@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

I'm a full stack software engineer and data scientist with 5+ years of experience as an industrial engineer and project manager. In my previous roles, I drove efficiency by integrating tools including AI, custom API's, Python scripts, and e-commerce websites that reduced order processing times by 25%.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILL

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JSON, Typescript, EJS

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Django, Bootstrap, AI,

Databases and other: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, API, Acumatica (ERP), BigCommerce, Postman

Interpersonal skills: Problem-solving, adaptive leadership, time management, empathy, collaboration

EXPERIENCE

Westridge Laboratories, Inc, Project Manager | Web Developer

Santa Ana, CA, 01/2021 - 06/2023

Orchestrated the successful launch of two distinct websites, overseeing end-to-end project execution. Coordinated cross-functional teams, ensuring seamless collaboration between design, development, content, and testing units.

- Achieved a 25% reduction in order processing times through the development of an eCommerce website.
- Created a Python script to execute the transition to a new SKU schema for the website automation project.
- Integrated AI into a custom application to improve customer experience.
- Developed APIs to automate daily tasks such as customer address sales tax verification and inventory management.

Westridge Laboratories, Inc, Industrial Engineer

Santa Ana, CA, 06/2019 - 01/2021

Remote, Graduated: 10/2023

Irvine, CA, US, Graduated: 12/2022

Sydney, Australia, Graduated: 02/2017

Buenos Aires, Argentina, Graduated: 12/2018

Implemented strategies to enhance production efficiency and reduce manufacturing costs, increasing the productivity and capacity of the company.

- Increased production capacity by 75% and cut production costs by 50% through automation of the production line.
- Implemented a new production line in less than a month to fulfill a client order.

Quilmes (AB-InBev), Project Manager

Buenos Aires, Argentina, 01/2018 - 01/2019

Selected for the "Industrial Talent Program" with the Project manager role during the stages of development, implementation, and control of the work philosophy "Autonomous operations" for South America.

- Conducted weekly meetings with senior managers to report KPIs performance and provide strategic insights.
- Facilitated seamless communication between cross-functional teams and senior management.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Trading App - GitHubAPI | GitHubClient | App - MERN, Express, React, node | React-Bootstrap, Mongoose Simulated space where individuals can practice and learn about trading financial assets without using real money.

- Leveraged the power of the MERN stack and React-Bootstrap to build a modern, dynamic platform.
- Powered by Node.js and Mongoose for robust back-end functionality.

Task Manager - GitHub | App - Python, Django | Materialize, SQL, AWS, Render, Neon

The Task Manager you always wanted to organize and manage your projects! Easy to use with a nice and smooth flow.

- Developed using the Django framework, leveraging its robust features for creating tasks and managing projects.
- Crafted user interface for aesthetics and an enhanced user experience, featuring a stylish design powered by Materialize, which provides a modern and responsive visual presentation.

Smoothie App - <u>GitHub</u> | <u>App</u> - <u>JavaScript</u>, CSS3, HTML5 | <u>Bootstrap</u>, EJS, <u>MongoDB</u>, MVC, API, fly.dev Create your favorite smoothie and share it with the world. More than 900,000 ingredients.

- Enhanced the user's experience using EJS to provide a real-time display of macronutrients.
- Utilized MongoDB for data storage, implemented an MVC architecture for organized structure, and integrated APIs.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive UCI, Certificate of Data Science UCA, Bachelors of Industrial Engineering UTS, University Exchange of Industrial Engineering